# **Bala Subrahmanyam Varanasi**

Email: <a href="mailto:vabasu@gmail.com">vabasu@gmail.com</a>
Mobile: +919985415959

## **Summary**

I'm a Software Developer and Entrepreneur having experience in the areas of Development, Design and Management of various Web and Mobile applications using Python/Django, Ruby on Rails and Android. I'm also an Open-Source Enthusiast, loves to read and teach open source tools.

## **Experience**

### Founder at Firebolt Labs, Aug 2014 – Present

Heading the day-to-day-operations, as well as handling the company's product and consulting projects.

## Software Developer at Crypsis Technologies, Sept 2013 - July 2014

Involved in the development of web and mobile apps using various technologies like Ruby on Rails, Android and NodeJS.

### Intern and Software Developer at Agiliq Info Solutions, Dec 2011 – Aug 2013

Worked with serveral clients across the globe on various projects and helped them in building various web and mobile apps using Python/Django and Android.

#### **Interests**

FOSS, Web Development, Mobile Development, Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence.

## **Key Skills**

Python, Django, Ruby on Rails, Flask, Android, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AngularJS, GIT, Ubuntu, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.

## **Projects**

## **Open Source**

- <u>Feature Development</u> in <u>django-graphos</u>.
- Bugfixes and pep8 improvements in scikit-learn.
- pep8 improvements in joblib.
- <u>Sentiment Analyzer</u>, a simple sentiment classification tool for Telugu Language.
- Feature Improvements and Test Cases in Join.agiliq.com
- Improvments to code samples in DjenOfDjango.

### **Django Applications**

- <u>Sufo</u>, an Educational Video site for Physicians.
- Feature Developments in <u>Suggestar</u>.
- Customized the Django Admin CMS for CineSport, an innovative web video syndication company.
- Feature Development in <u>TravelDojo</u>, a company to create travel guides to the Southeast Asia region.
- Testing and Bugfixes Ocassio Health Strategies.
- Seeded <u>HyderabadWiki</u> with Wikipedia dump in LocalWiki Format.
- The Xaming Arena, a simple Online Examination system using Django framework.

#### **Ruby on Rails Applications**

- Mr Delicious, an online food delivery system.
- <u>Investment Club</u> by <u>StockViews</u>.
- Feature Development in <u>Swym</u>.
- <u>Virtual Analyst</u> by <u>Analytics Intelligence</u>.
- Feature Developments and Test Cases Development in Mega Golf Virtual League.

### **Android Applications**

- "Windows Ambassador", an application by Microsoft.
- "Where's My App?", checks the availability status of apps and games in the Windows Phone Store.
- "Baby Names", a simple android app to choose a baby name.

## **Publications**

"Python Requests Essentials", a book which showcases fundamental as well as advanced Python Requests concepts.

## **Education**

- **Batchelor of Technology**, Information Technology from Vishnu Institute of Technology, 2008 2012.
- **Intermediate Education** from Santhiniketan Junior College, 2006 2008.
- SSC from G.V&K.B.M School, 2006.

## As a Speaker

PyCon India, 2013; SciPy 2011 & 2013 and CoDec 2012.